Contact

pattybbs@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/patricia-i-b01213133 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

social services
Spanish
Interpersonal Skills

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Spanish (Native or Bilingual)
French (Limited Working)

Certifications

Tech advocate

Patricia Idrugo

Bilingual Watch Me Grow Coordinator at Gatepath San Mateo, California

Summary

As a care coordinator, I provide developmental and social-emotional screenings, referral and care coordination services for children from birth to five years. In addition, I facilitate timely access to assessment and services for children with special needs and families requiring additional support in pediatric clinics and family support settings.

Experience

Gatepath
Bilingual Watch Me Grow Coordinator
March 2019 - Present
Redwood City, California

Provide information to families and programs on of the value of developmental screening and the value of desired early intervention outcomes for children at risk for or with special needs and developmental disabilities.

Administer required screenings and program forms, including but not limited to consent forms, intake and follow-up interviews and demographic information.

Make appropriate referrals for community and developmental services in

coordination with the team and the child study team recommendations, following the first 5 San Mateo screening and services protocol.

Provide case management to assist families in accessing needed services to ensure that the child and/or family needs were met through the referral process.

Maintain current and accurate client records and prepare reports on case management activities for a large case load, entering client data into multiple databases.

Develop collaborative relationships with community agencies, project lead agencies, and partners to identify families with children eligible for care coordination services within the targeted geographic area.

Provide Spanish translation to ensure culturally competent processes, service delivery, and resources for families.

CORA - Community Overcoming Relationship Abuse Bilingual Counselor/Case Manager May 2015 - March 2019 (3 years 11 months) San Mateo

Schedule, screen, and perform intake and assessments for new residents entering CORA safe Houses.

Respond to callers on the 24-hr hotline, ERP and housing departments evenings, weekends, and holidays.

Provide immediate crisis response, needs assessment, and conduct safety planning with all callers and/or residents

Provide crisis intervention, conflict resolution support, and de-escalation intervention for residents on-site

Provide case management and advocacy support to a caseload of residents and/or families experiencing domestic violence and other co-existing conditions such as mental disorders, disabilities, substance abuse, sexual trafficking,etc

Create client-centered service plans and utilize motivational interviewing to empower and encourage clients to achieve self-sufficiency goals

Familiarity with housing, financial empowerment, career counseling and other community services in the San Mateo, Santa Clara and San Francisco County Facilitate resident activities, support groups, weekly community meetings, and other educational workshops as needed.

Complete required documentation and data into client database in an accurate and timely manner. Maintain up to date client files, records, and reports.

Support interdepartmental communication in order to support better clients

Assist in compiling program statistics, maintenance of filing systems, and

Recruit, train, supervise, and schedule volunteers to support safe house staff and residents using trauma informed approach

development/implementation of new protocols and procedures.

Train and mentor new safe house employees

Collaborate effectively with other departments and outside agencies to ensure successful service delivery

Conduct community outreach, as needed, to optimize referral relationships with partner agencies.

QuantiView
Data entry Marketing specialist
2011 - 2012 (1 year)

San Mateo

 Sorted, reconciled and kept records of client's preferences to prepare reports
 Assisted team with ongoing administrative and operational tasks
 Managed and imported data
 Supported and contributed to various projects and reporting requests.

BURLINGAME MOTHERS CLUB

International Mamas coordinator 2008 - 2011 (3 years)

Burlingame

Organized and maintain member's database
 Promoted internal
and external activities to attract new members
 Organized events that
support members to engage in family based activities while still considering
multicultural diversity

La Casa de las Madres Bilingual Family advocate 2001 - 2002 (1 year)

Provide crisis intervention and counseling by telephone or in person;

Provide field accompaniment to clients as needed - medical, criminal justice, civil legal & social services;

Provide comprehensive assessments that will result in individual care plans; Coordinate linkages and work collaboratively with community-based organizations to ensure accessibility and greater options for clients and their families:

Collaborate with on-site consultants/clinicians to provide comprehensive services to high risk clients;# maintain for safekeeping, client files in compliance with grant and/or contract guidelines;

Assist with day to day operations including phone coverage, site supervision, crisis intervention, and conflict resolution;

Participate in regularly scheduled staff and case management meetings; Maintain and submit program documentation in accordance with grant requirements; and

Facilitate a variety of support groups.

Aerocontinente

Reservations Supervisor/Airline Instructor January 1995 - December 2001 (7 years)

Lima, Peru

Supervised airline inbound call center.

Trained and mentored more than 60+ agents

Supported professional growth considering personal interests and airline goals and expectations

Decreased waiting time response by 15% by training staff to answer calls effectively

Created and updated training materials that agents used to improve their customer skills, sales, minimize conflict and guarantee customer satisfaction. Scheduled quarterly trainings and invite relevant departments to provide feedback to improve company's communications

Trained reservations agents and helped them to master the In-house reservations system.

Created and updated schedules for more than 60+agents with 3 overlapping schedules.

Supported IT's helpdesk and troubleshooted common reservation computer errors in a daily basis.

Created an annual review format that was widely spread and used by Airline managers.

Education

General Assembly

Front-end web development, Information Technology (2018 - 2019)

Cañada College

Associate's Degree, Human Services, General · (2014 - 2017)

Universidad de San Martín de Porres

Bachelor's Degree, Tourism and Hospitality administration (2000)